Memory burns.
Aftersun is a drama film directed by Charlotte Wells.
Sophie reflects on the shared joy and private melancholy of a
holiday she took with her father twenty years earlier.
Memories fill the gaps between camcorder footages as she tries to
reconcile the father she knew with the troubled man she didn't.
Calum, played by Paul Mescal.
Sophie, played by Frankie Corio.
Michael, played by Brooklyn Toulson.
Adult Sophie, played by Celia Rowlson-Hall.
Belinda, played by Sally Messham.
Teen Girl 1, played by Ayşe Parlak.
Aftersun is a 2022 semi-autobiographical coming-of-age drama film written and
directed by Charlotte Wells in her feature directorial debut.
Starring Paul Mescal, Frankie Corio, and Celia Rowlson-Hall, the film is loosely based on Wells' childhood and follows an
11-year-old Scottish girl on holiday with her father at a Turkish resort on the eve of his 31st birthday.
Aftersun had its world premiere at the Cannes Film Festival on 21 May
2022, where Wells was nominated for the Caméra d'Or.
It was theatrically released in the United States on 21
October and in the United Kingdom on 18 November.
The film received widespread acclaim from critics, who praised the direction,
screenplay, cinematography, visuals, and performances of Corio and Mescal.
Aftersun received four nominations at the 76th BAFTA Awards, where Wells won
for Outstanding Debut by a British Writer, Director or Producer.
Mescal was nominated as Best Lead Actor at the 95th Academy Awards, in
addition to receiving BAFTA nomination in the same category.
The National Board of Review named Aftersun one of the best films of 2022 and Sight
and Sound ranked it first on its list of the best films of 2022.
Since then, it has been cited as among the best films
of the 2020s and the 21st century.
The film explores themes of hotel, depression, karaoke, tourist, melancholy.
The tone is emotional.